<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentList>
	<!-- 1, 11 -->
	<content contentuid="fcf5d1d3-3d8d-4ca3-9f13-10d6d81cb9a8" version="1">"He who fights with monsters should look to it that he himself does not become a monster... when you gaze long into the abyss the abyss also gazes into you..." - Friedrich Nietzsche.</content>
	<!-- 2 -->
	<content contentuid="5296b658-4e4f-4bde-8ff8-36f20b3ffb13" version="1">"The Lord of Murder shall perish, but in his doom he shall spawn a score of mortal progeny. Chaos will be sewn from their passage." - So sayeth the wise Alaundo.</content>
	<!-- 3 -->
	<content contentuid="3f3dea23-b427-4afd-8a2f-d0cb781b2caa" version="1">"If he were to succeed there is no doubt I would be among the dead, but my name would live on in his wake. There are things beyond death if you die in the right fashion, and how could there not be a place in history for the architect that shaped the actions of the ascending Lord of Murder? You would not understand; you were born to affect the Realms. The rest of us must carve our own place by whatever means necessary." - Winski Perorate.</content>
	<!-- 4 -->
	<content contentuid="53e271e7-755c-4967-882c-d24a4e5374f2" version="1">"The Dream Eater. It is said the children of Bhaal are claimed throughout their sleep, ever-disturbed by visions of a life of bloodshed and terror. Once they have seen too much, once these dreams drive their minds to break, they are beset by the Slayer." - Volothamp Geddarm.</content>
	<!-- 5 -->
	<content contentuid="6c2fb862-489e-4150-9596-8dc0b2d9d31a" version="1">"Know ye that there is one god above all the gods of Faerun, a being known as Ao, the One Who Is Hidden. Ao it was, so we are told, who created the gods, to bring order out of chaos, so that our world could exist, each beast in its place and each plant in its niche, all in harmony. Standard talk, I know, but evidently true." - Elminster.</content>
	<!-- 6 - If we get that far on initial load -->
	<content contentuid="37d0f03b-ae39-4384-b1d5-391b2e644455" version="1">*Squeak* - Boo.</content>
	<!-- 7 -->
	<content contentuid="78132664-62d9-4b51-a972-109b8f1ad693" version="1">"The cultists who blaspheme reality by calling out to Elder Evils often speak of a Far Realm from which these entities hail. In truth, there is no one place or space from which they come. There is the multiverse of things that are, and there is the multiverse of things that shouldn't be." - Mordenkainen.</content>
	<!-- 8, 10 -->
	<content contentuid="53987a46-ac4a-4662-8b45-628cb438887d" version="1">"These things also I have observed: that knowledge of our world is to be nurtured like a precious flower, for it is the most precious thing we have. Wherefore guard the word written and heed words unwritten—and set them down ere they fade... Learn then, well, the arts of reading, writing, and listening true, and they will lead you to the greatest art of all: understanding." - Alaundo of Candlekeep.</content>
	<!-- 9 -->
	<content contentuid="8fc93388-faa6-4f97-8955-7ad50d9ab6f2" version="1">"The Hells are not so simple to understand. Boiling down nine cosmological layers into 'evil, but with a few more rules' does generations of scholars discredit. Each layer is its own unique moral and magical ecosystem. What Zariel permits in Avernus may be blasphemy to Mammon in the chained cities of Minauros. The Hells bend not only to their whim and will, but to their mere presence. The more souls they acquire, the more that combined influence spreads." - A letter from Sylvira Savikas.</content>
	<!-- 12 -->
	<content contentuid="d3e51c41-a6c3-42f3-a741-1bc9cbdbae80" version="1">"The planes exist in a precarious state. A seemingly small event could echo across the worlds and tip the Balance. My task is to keep a finger on each end of the scales, ensuring it never sways too violently." - Mordenkainen.</content>
	<!-- 13 -->
	<content contentuid="79f42e9a-4891-4eb9-8e62-57d1c04cd38a" version="1">"My legions are the only thing standing between your precious Seven Heavens and the bottomless hunger of the Abyss. I did not fall into the clutches of evil. I rose to shoulder a cosmic burden." - Zariel.</content>
	<!-- 14 -->
	<content contentuid="94d0f352-4555-4174-995c-ec8a5dacac50" version="1">"Evil is not an absence of good. […] It is not a choice. […] Evil is one of two forces in the cosmos, an agency locked in eternal struggle against its antithesis. […] Only good and evil exist. And not even a hair's width of space separates them." - Vecna.</content>

	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="e79feae3-9916-4876-b33d-f756342451df" version="1">"Justice? Justice had never been more than a façade and a means of keeping the pretense of order in chaotic Menzoberranzan." - Matron SiNafay Hun'ett of Menzoberranzan's ruling council.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="3c46d604-6380-493a-bdf9-89fb32013052" version="1">"In the end all things betray you. Honor. Ideals. Heroism. Allies. Comrades. Lovers. Your eyes. Your limbs. Your heart. And in the end, you betray yourself. And that is the greatest betrayal of all." - The lament of Zaxarus, cambion "hero" of the Blood War.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="577eafce-8c70-43c1-ba78-8c5d8440bd15" version="1">"They break before our shields, they fall beneath our blades; Their home is ours to conquer, their children our slaves. Acheron! Acheron! Victory is ours!" - The translation of a hobgoblin war chant.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="bf1ee36c-30ef-4a4e-aeb5-14c41d31f4c4" version="1">"Those who destroy knowledge, with ink, fire, or sword, are themselves destroyed." - Candlekeep's one absolute rule.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="69b30313-a8bf-46d6-a2c4-1c9127656854" version="1">"Didn't you hear Ao? There was no crime. Leira died because I willed it. Any of you could be next. That's my place in the Balance: To weed out the weak from this pathetic pantheon." - Cyric, to his fellow greater powers.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="8a4a33da-84ca-4856-bf0c-b44ba6965a6c" version="1">"Ooh, the sneaky rascals. If it wasn't for the rampant egotism, random murdering, and foul gods, I might quite like these Zhentarim." - Purfbin Doogrick</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="a92e0a7f-aee5-42a3-8335-83c1efc32583" version="1">"You are no god, priestess of Bhaal. You play with stolen energies that make you immortal, that give you great power...but that does not make you a god." - Solar.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="109cf068-f8c1-4ee3-bd22-bae47f18b539" version="1">"The gods are stirring, mark my words, and in a way we've never seen before. The wars? The way powers who were content to bide their time have all leaped at each others' throats?―if that isn't the hand of the gods moving things, I don't know what is." - The Harper Tharra.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="dcd0aacf-b2d5-4283-9513-7f2c41b13a1e" version="1">"I hope you're satisfied. Look at my clothing! Caked-on mud everywhere! Do you have any idea how many hairy, four-legged BEASTS I had to avoid while making my way here? Woofs, were they? Wharves? I don't know." - Baeloth Barrityl.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="7e6a768f-ab42-4d31-b968-b400932a652f" version="1">"My 'otels as clean as an elven arse!" - Winthrop, Candlekeep innkeeper.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="34d06c2f-6b5d-4855-bdd9-9e79860a482f" version="1">"N-no! Not replacing, good heavens no, just assisting! How could I turn down such an editor as Elminster? It would be an affront to Mystra—er—to all my fans!" - Volothamp Geddarm.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="eac5fa97-dbf4-46f4-8f53-0016be791f0c" version="1">"An idea has no heft but it can move mountains. An idea has no authority but it can dominate people. An idea has no strength but it can push aside empires. Knowledge is the greatest tool of the mortal mind, outweighing anything made by mortal hands. Before anything can exist, the idea must exist." - An aphorism and common prayer of Oghma's faithful.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="22fe1322-7f27-4f31-b2ff-aa4ce7fa4a36" version="1">"There are many worlds, young elf. The Shadow Deep connects them all. It's the one mirror that shapes their many lights." - Melegaunt Tanthul, Nightal 24 1371 DR.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="d81d0b07-0523-4de4-8def-6b63b68d626a" version="1">"As long as I exist, slavery will always be a way of life here in Thay. And I can promise you, I will be here for a very long time." - Szass Tam.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="28cef7d5-1646-4677-a1e5-4889334836b4" version="1">"An orc life is a god-ridden life. Luthic's at birth, Luthic's at death, and striving to prove themselves to Gruumsh in between." - Elminster's notes in Volo's Guide to Monsters.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="15bc74a9-16db-493f-8963-75460391f299" version="1">"Thus are the four Pains spread through the multiverse—agony, anguish, misery, and despair—to ripen and burst and bring low the mighty and the meek alike." - Lady of Pain.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="78ec52c0-d041-400b-8110-6279e34ce039" version="1">"Blasted Netherese sense of humor! No doubt this is why they all went extinct so long ago! Shut up! Shut up, I say!" - Edwin Odesseiron.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="252ee6d6-4d26-4457-9962-6e8be0268500" version="1">"Some scholars number and name the parts of the Abyss, declaring that this demon lord or that rules a portion of the place. When your house is on fire, does it matter what the flames look like in each room? Should you bother to give them names? What's important is escaping and putting out any fire that clings to you." - Mordenkainen.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="6c9f1047-fcab-473b-b8e1-8201d122c6bb" version="1">"Undermountain? Ah, yes. A great place to have fun, the most famous battlefield in which to earn a reputation as a veteran adventurer — and the largest known mass grave in Faerûn today." - Elminster.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="99ef84b0-1e96-492f-8e3c-99082fa56051" version="1">"From the shadows of chaos, two sisters are born, One bright Selûne, the other dark Shar. A harmonious balance soon to be torn When Selûne gifts life with flame from afar!" - An excerpt from a ballad by Veseene the Lark.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="c5daedab-4e5d-4228-a6c0-3ed8f2fb999d" version="1">"Demogorgon is his own worst enemy. He is, in many ways, two creatures that share the same body. Aeumal, his left head, is the more charismatic and calculating while Hethradiah, his right head, is more impulsive and feral. Each views the other as inferior and each believes the other incapable of outfoxing itself." - Shami-Amourae, former consort of Demogorgon.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="3b38d426-05df-4cb5-8a8c-1233e99c2287" version="1">"Dragons? Splendid things, lad - so long as ye look upon them only in tapestries, or in the masks worn at revels, or from about three realms off." - Astragarl Hornwood, Mage of Elembar.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="f443e33e-af1f-4afd-8119-4c1197158780" version="1">"For ruin had risen in thunderous fury, A ravenous shadow fell over the shore. And when Father Dagon's black gullet gaped open the waves ran with blood and the isle was no more." - Excerpt from a traditional sea shanty.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="81d147ea-7d5e-4274-88eb-897853e24514" version="1">"Three peaks to seem as one, Behind ye the morning sun." - Bruenor Battlehammer reciting the first part of a dwarven song, whilst at Fourthpeak.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="1384c760-622b-4acc-9d36-a651f7924617" version="1">"…An' then of a sudden I heard this call like a trumpet. Deafed me, it did. All th' fiends turned, looked 'round, couldna see nothin'. Above sudden came this huuuge light from nowhere! It burned 'em! It burned ever'thing! It burned my brain!" - Danis Twelve-Fingers, scribe of Sigil, describing a battle of fiends against angels that left a 200-foot vertical crater in the slopes of Mount Celestia.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="fdeed173-d3f6-4365-85f0-a1c66b5bdf43" version="1">"We are the Harpers. We are the Lord Protectors of the Realms, Fools, all―but the Gods look down and smile glory upon us. Weep for us, watch for us, and hope in us. We shall not fail thee." - Harper Chant, composed by Ailadrea Stars-in-mist.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="b61309e8-da94-4ea3-b732-ee76f3ed9622" version="1">"Let me be your eyes, Blind One, and cast your justice upon this world." - A basic prayer to Tyr.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="4eba8b22-6ae2-48eb-a2e6-a09b87476f42" version="1">"Children? Pawns, more likely, dancing dolls for the Spider Queen, puppets on the imperceptible but impervious strands of her web. All climb the Spider Queen's ladders; all hunt for her pleasure; and all fall to the hunters of her pleasure." - Drizzt Do'Urden.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="76031d21-3dab-4796-8339-3129fdb078cf" version="1">"Helm sees the world as nothing but some vague prize to be protected from an even more vague adversary. That would have to be Mask, I suppose. Who would the God of Guardians hate more than the Patron of Thieves?" - The reincarnated Mystra regarding Helm.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="f4dc92d4-298a-4053-a345-308483f97b81" version="1">"Think ye weave cunning schemes and elaborate intrigues with fallback plans and positions? Beholders change, refine, discard, and spin anew scores of such plans all the time. To the average beholder, human intrigues are the fumbling of babies." - Elminster's notes in Volo's Guide to Monsters.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="3660fbc9-484d-4948-ad81-b264a5560d86" version="1">"Every fall of the hammer on the anvil, every fire stoked in the forge, is a step on a journey set before me by Moradin himself. It isn't work. It is a challenge to achieve greatness." - Balifra Eversharp.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="1db5b5a9-9e19-4e2d-bc74-a6d5f7e1d95e" version="1">"When the ending draws near, with ice-locked stars unmoving, the threefold threats await, and the herald proclaims, in war-wrecked misery, announcing the dying of an age." - The final stanza of Elliandreth's prophecy.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="27c6285a-eb09-4233-af69-43ff88b50805" version="1">"I have tried to recreate it, tried to spark it anew in my memory, but it is gone...a hollow, dead thing. For years I clung to the memory of it. Then the memory of the memory. And then nothing-the Seldarine took that from me too." - Irenicus "the Exile".</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="162326b2-cc56-4806-b5d0-f309c1611518" version="1">"We shall rule them from an Iron Throne, built of the weapons of our trade..." - Sfena in 1347 DR.</content>
	<!--  -->
	<content contentuid="8a88bd23-6558-427a-86df-1488b5339f3a" version="1">"I choose death...I can destroy your kingdom, Bane, by murdering your subjects, and I can starve your kingdom, Myrkul, by staying my hand." - Bhaal.</content>
</contentList>