<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentList>
	<content contentuid="78132664-62d9-4b51-a972-109b8f1ad693" version="1">Vortex will be getting replaced by a brand new mod manager from Nexus in the future, in collaboration with the minds behind Wabbajack! They should call it Nexus Mod Manager 2 Wabbavortex Electric Boogaloo!</content>
	<content contentuid="e79feae3-9916-4876-b33d-f756342451df" version="1">Did you know you can disable the Larian launcher and jump straight into the game? It can be done through Steam by putting "--skip-launcher" into the Launch Options for the game, found under Properties &gt; General. Or through BG3MM, by toggling "Skip Launcher" in Preferences &gt; General.</content>
	<content contentuid="d3e51c41-a6c3-42f3-a741-1bc9cbdbae80" version="1">"The Lord of Murder shall perish, but in his doom he shall spawn a score of mortal progeny. Chaos will be sewn from their passage." - So sayeth the wise Alaundo.</content>
	<content contentuid="6c2fb862-489e-4150-9596-8dc0b2d9d31a" version="1">The Antristrophic Filtering graphics setting is broken, it makes beards and short head hairs look blocky. A way to get around this is to force "16x Anisotropic Filtering" in your graphics card's 3D settings software for bg3_dx11.exe.</content>
	<content contentuid="3c46d604-6380-493a-bdf9-89fb32013052" version="1">Don't sleep on your new Common Actions! Dodge enemy attacks, trade Actions for Bonus Actions or Reactions, Grapple enemies to hold them in place (requires a free hand), or punch enemies with a weapon equipped... if you want to, for whatever reason.</content>
	<content contentuid="577eafce-8c70-43c1-ba78-8c5d8440bd15" version="1">Huge thanks to Norbyte (Script Extender/Lslib), LaughingLeader (BG3MM), ShinyHobo (Modders Multitool), Pavelk/Caites (basically every UI mod), and all the other mod authors who make our modded fun possible!</content>
	<content contentuid="bf1ee36c-30ef-4a4e-aeb5-14c41d31f4c4" version="1">Loading a save which is in mid-combat will not have Combat Extender health buffs apply properly, it is what it is.</content>
	<content contentuid="8fc93388-faa6-4f97-8955-7ad50d9ab6f2" version="1">Want Honour Mode changes without the hassle of a single save file? Grab "Honour Features Unlocker" from the optional mods! Give bosses those legendary actions and acquire more authentic tabletop balancing! Fighter/Warlock multi-class getting 2 Extra Attacks before a pure Fighter? Not anymore!</content>
	<content contentuid="53987a46-ac4a-4662-8b45-628cb438887d" version="1">Don't forget to follow instructions when updating the collection. Read the changelog(s), check for optional mod updates and clean up leftover files.</content>
	<content contentuid="37d0f03b-ae39-4384-b1d5-391b2e644455" version="1">Haven't played the original Baldur's Gate I and II? Play those when you're done with Baldur's Gate 3! Otherwise Boo will bite us all in hard to reach places!</content>
	<content contentuid="69b30313-a8bf-46d6-a2c4-1c9127656854" version="1">Please report any bugs to me in Discord under #bug-reports so I can patch them! Even very little things, like tooltip grammar and punctuation!</content>
	<content contentuid="fcf5d1d3-3d8d-4ca3-9f13-10d6d81cb9a8" version="1">Preferably launch the game directly from the bg3_dx11.exe, found in the game's Bin folder. Create a desktop shortcut for easy access. Don't launch from Vortex. If you're launching the from BG3MM: Toggle "Enable DirectX 11 Mode" under Preferences &gt; General. Launching from Steam is fine, assuming it won't update the game prematurely.</content>
	<content contentuid="8a4a33da-84ca-4856-bf0c-b44ba6965a6c" version="1">Enjoying Difficulty, Immersion, Quality? Don't forget to give the collection an Endorsement! Smash that thumbs up button!</content>
	<content contentuid="a92e0a7f-aee5-42a3-8335-83c1efc32583" version="1">Your combat needs some extra spice? Download "Absolute Wrath" found in the optional mods! With semi-random affixes applied to enemies at the beginning of combat, every fight is unique!</content>
	<content contentuid="109cf068-f8c1-4ee3-bd22-bae47f18b539" version="1">Running the Equipment Library optional mod? Medium and Heavy armour reduce movement speed, customise your builds to compensate for this drawback.</content>
	<content contentuid="dcd0aacf-b2d5-4283-9513-7f2c41b13a1e" version="1">There are still plenty of bugs which Larian is responsible for, I am not in complete control of your game experience. Patches introduce more bugs, Hotfixes try to fix them without making more. This is just the nature of things, given the game is still under active developement.</content>
	<content contentuid="7e6a768f-ab42-4d31-b968-b400932a652f" version="1">Playing on Honour Mode? Use caution! Keep backup saves from your AppData &gt; Local &gt; Larian Studios &gt; Baldur's Gate 3 &gt; PlayerProfiles &gt; Public &gt; Savegames &gt; Story folder. I do not recommend Honour Mode when running so many mods, or even due to the amount of vanilla bugs. Reloading can be a good friend!</content>
	<content contentuid="34d06c2f-6b5d-4855-bdd9-9e79860a482f" version="1">Damaging attacks aren't always the best way to overcome combat encounters. Stealth, consumables, crowd control magic, the environment, buffs and debuffs; use everything at your disposal.</content>
	<content contentuid="eac5fa97-dbf4-46f4-8f53-0016be791f0c" version="1">Finding the game too challenging? Not challenging enough? Combat Extender adds spells and abilities to enemies, controls their level based stat increases and health multipliers. Feel free to edit my config file for it!</content>
	<content contentuid="22fe1322-7f27-4f31-b2ff-aa4ce7fa4a36" version="1">Water and lightning is not the only damage combo anymore. Shocked/Shocking Grasp = Radiant. Feeble/Contagion/Eyebite Sick = Necrotic. Frightened/Feared = Psychic. Paralysed/Hold Person = Force. Reverberate = Thunder. Bleeding/Gaping Wound = Poison/Acid. Poisoned/Enwebbed/Entangled = Fire.</content>
	<content contentuid="d81d0b07-0523-4de4-8def-6b63b68d626a" version="1">Randomising appearance in character creation will likely lead to some less than desirable outcomes. For example, slots such as the Dragonborn Jaw, or Horns can be used for layering hairstyles if you wish. There's a great number of options, and you're best to build your character piece by piece.</content>
	<content contentuid="28cef7d5-1646-4677-a1e5-4889334836b4" version="1">You may notice that equipable items which do not stack in vanilla do stack in this collection. Split individual items off stacks prior to equipping them!</content>
	<content contentuid="5296b658-4e4f-4bde-8ff8-36f20b3ffb13" version="1">Hopefully you have your game's auto updates disabled! The collection will not be functional for a few days when new BG3 patches drop, refer to 2: Updating Guide - Collection &amp; Game Updates on the collection page.</content>
	<content contentuid="15bc74a9-16db-493f-8963-75460391f299" version="1">Missing abilities? Drag all of the red shutter bars on your hotbar to the left, the final pane will appear. The vanilla game's concertina is merged with the regular hotbar.</content>
	<content contentuid="78ec52c0-d041-400b-8110-6279e34ce039" version="1">Speak with Dead has no question limit, and you can speak with damage corpses. The Speak with Dead status will not be cleared with a short rest, it will only be removed if you unlearn the spell from your spellbook; with few exceptions.</content>
	<content contentuid="79f42e9a-4891-4eb9-8e62-57d1c04cd38a" version="1">Exhaustion is gained primarily through combat and removed with either a Short or Long Rest. There are 7 levels of Exhaustion, your stats will temporarily and incrementally reduced whenever you fail a relevant DC 15 Constitution Saving Throw. You will roll for Exhaustion when hit with a Critical Hit, knocked Prone, set on Fire, etc.</content>
	<content contentuid="252ee6d6-4d26-4457-9962-6e8be0268500" version="1">A few powerful enemies can not be disarmed of their shiny weapons! No more can you take weapons from imposing enemies like candy from a baby!</content>
	<content contentuid="6c9f1047-fcab-473b-b8e1-8201d122c6bb" version="1">Seeing unobtainable loot in the tooltip's preview window? This is intended 99% of the time, with the exception being bugs. There is an exploit to get those items though, check out 4: Everything Else You Need to Know on the collection page.</content>
	<content contentuid="94d0f352-4555-4174-995c-ec8a5dacac50" version="1">For best performance and stability play the game in fullscreen with DX11. 32GB of RAM is highly recommended. For further performance information view 4: Everything Else You Need to Know on the collection page.</content>
	<content contentuid="99ef84b0-1e96-492f-8e3c-99082fa56051" version="1">Don't like the contextual UI? You can find instructions for swapping out the auto-hide versions of these mods under 4: Everything Else You Need to Know on the collection page.</content>
	<content contentuid="c5daedab-4e5d-4228-a6c0-3ed8f2fb999d" version="1">Finding all of the class options intimidating? Vanilla classes and subclasses are still very much viable. Not every custom class or subclass is more powerful than vanilla options, many are of a similar caliber. Paladin level 2/College of Sword Bard level 10 still slays.</content>
	<content contentuid="3b38d426-05df-4cb5-8a8c-1233e99c2287" version="1">Feel like a spamming a button for a moment? You can toggle the column for "Endorsed" on the Vortex "Mods" page, and from there give the ole' thumbs up to all the mods in this collection!</content>
	<content contentuid="f443e33e-af1f-4afd-8119-4c1197158780" version="1">All classes can now choose deities! If you wish to opt out of deity selection, choose Faithful or Faithless, these are the only options without dialogue tags associated.</content>
	<content contentuid="81d147ea-7d5e-4274-88eb-897853e24514" version="1">Running more than 4 party members? Keep in mind there are certain points in the game which are hardcoded for 4 party members, refer the mod page for Aether's No Party Limits. You must un-gather your oversized party before venturing forth.</content>
	<content contentuid="1384c760-622b-4acc-9d36-a651f7924617" version="1">WASD Character Movement can be toggled on and off with the CAPS lock key, walking can be toggled with Insert, and Shift+W toggles auto-run.</content>
	<content contentuid="3f3dea23-b427-4afd-8a2f-d0cb781b2caa" version="1">If you encounter issues be sure to read over the collection page prior to seeking assistance, primarily 3: Troubleshooting Guides and 4: Everything Else You Need to Know!</content>
	<content contentuid="fdeed173-d3f6-4365-85f0-a1c66b5bdf43" version="1">"He who fights with monsters should look to it that he himself does not become a monster... when you gaze long into the abyss the abyss also gazes into you..." - Friedrich Nietzsche.</content>
	<content contentuid="b61309e8-da94-4ea3-b732-ee76f3ed9622" version="1">Wanting to customise this collection? Be careful! With this many mods conflicts can happen easily, instead post a mod you'd like to see in the #suggestions channel on Discord.</content>
	<content contentuid="4eba8b22-6ae2-48eb-a2e6-a09b87476f42" version="1">A Critical Miss? Somebody gets to take a free Attack of Opportunity! Capitalise on the folly of your enemies, or get punished for your own.</content>
	<content contentuid="76031d21-3dab-4796-8339-3129fdb078cf" version="1">Gale will actually help your 8 Intelligence Tav with those Arcana checks! Your companions' skills actually help out in dialogue, thanks to the mod Use Highest Modifier in Dialogue!</content>
	<content contentuid="53e271e7-755c-4967-882c-d24a4e5374f2" version="1">Vendors drop all of their loot upon death. Unbalanced? Maybe. Immersive and convenient? Yes.</content>
	<content contentuid="f4dc92d4-298a-4053-a345-308483f97b81" version="1">Withers can be traded with! He sells all sorts of custom items such as vanity clothing, debug and convenience items, some custom weapons etc. Take a look at the bottom left buttons when speaking with him!</content>
	<content contentuid="3660fbc9-484d-4948-ad81-b264a5560d86" version="1">Optional mods are optional for a reason, please read about them prior to installing them.</content>
	<content contentuid="1db5b5a9-9e19-4e2d-bc74-a6d5f7e1d95e" version="1">Many spells, abilities and items have been rebalanced! Grossly overpowered "must have" build choices are brought down to earth, and many others aren't useless!</content>
	<content contentuid="27c6285a-eb09-4233-af69-43ff88b50805" version="1">Don't forget to grab my customised configuration files! Take a look at the Combat Extender Nexus page and Github to see how you can further customise encounters!</content>
	<content contentuid="162326b2-cc56-4806-b5d0-f309c1611518" version="1">The Script Extender console window can be used for a multitude of functions, you can spawn in items and add abilities, run mod related commands, or even fix vanilla bugs. Check out #console-commands in the Discord.</content>
	<content contentuid="8a88bd23-6558-427a-86df-1488b5339f3a" version="1">The instrument equipment slot is now useful for all! Keep an eye out for trinkets on your adventures, there's something to compliment all play styles!</content>
</contentList>